==========================================================================================================================================

Privacy Policy
==============

The RightsStatements.org Consortium collects, manages and uses your data so that we can run our services and share relevant content with you. This policy describes how we collect and use your data when you use our services through the website or in person, and the measures we take to ensure your data remains secure. Europeana Foundation runs these services on behalf of the RightsStatements.org Consortium and takes responsibility for these data.

Keeping your data secure
------------------------

Your privacy is important to us. We take all steps necessary to ensure that your data is stored securely and used only in accordance with the preferences you have requested. We will not share your data unless you have given us permission to share it. We do not and will not sell your data. Where possible, we use services that are hosted within the European Union.

Collecting your data
--------------------

### We collect information through cookies

When you use a RightsStatements.org website, we use [cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) to collect information about your settings and preferences so that these can be used each time you visit one of our websites. We also collect information that is not specific to your identity such as information collected automatically through cookies, e.g. your language preferences.

Managing your data
------------------

You can manage cookies by checking the settings for each browser you use.

We do not keep your data for any longer than necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we collected the data or the purposes for which data are reused.

You may ask us whether we process data relating to you, and if so, which data this concerns. In that case, we can provide you with access to the data processed by us that relates to you. If you believe your personal data has been processed incorrectly or incompletely, you may request that we change or supplement the data (rectification).

You can contact us via [\[email protected\]](https://rightsstatements.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

If you have a complaint concerning the processing of your personal data by the RightsStatements.org Consortium or Europeana Foundation, please

1. contact us via [\[email protected\]](https://rightsstatements.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection);
2. contact your local Data Protection Authority (DPA).

Using your data
---------------

There are a number of ways that we may use or share your data in order to provide our services. If we intend to use or share your data for purposes other than those described here, we will inform you when we request your data. We will only use your data upon your approval and/or if it is necessary to perform agreements.

### Analytics

#### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to understand our users’ needs and optimise our service (e.g. how many views each page receives, whether people return to our website, what routes people take through our web pages). Google Analytics only stores anonymised information, such as browser type, operating system, visit time, country of access and anonymised IP addresses. Google Analytics data is stored in accordance with their own privacy policy, which is available by clicking [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

What this policy applies to
---------------------------

This privacy policy applies to the use of services provided by the RightsStatements.org Consortium. It is in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union.

Updates
-------

This page was last updated 4 June 2019. If you have any questions for us or suggestions on how to improve the information on this page, please contact us via [\[email protected\]](https://rightsstatements.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

RightsStatements.org is an international member based consortium, supported by public funding.

Except where otherwise noted, content on this site is licensed under a [CC0 Public Domain Dedication](https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/).
